Saurav Modi

400 E 33Rd St, Chicago, Illinois - 60616 | (312)-478-1958 | sauravmodi03@gmail.com/smodi@depaul.edu | https://www.linkedin.com/in/sauravmodi03

Profile:

Full-stack developer with expertise in developing backend and frontend Software Solutions using Java, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Acquired significant experience in working with a wide range of web frameworks, such as Angular, Spring Boot, Bootstrap, React, and Ionic.

Education:

2022 - PRESENT | DEPAUL UNIVERSITY | CHICAGO, USA

3.75/4

Master of Computer Science

Course Work: Distributed System, Concepts of Programming Language, Fundamental of Data Science, Applied Algorithm & Structures, Software Engineering, Data Analysis & Regression

2012 - 2016 | SAVITRIBAI PHULE PUNE UNIVERSITY | PUNE, INDIA

3.35/4

Bachelor of Computer Engineering

Key Skills:

Object-Oriented Design (OOD) | Test-Driven Development (TDD) | Web Application Development | Agile methodologies | Project Management | Team Handling | Design Patterns

- Programming Languages: Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python
- Frameworks: Angular, Spring Boot, Bootstrap, REST APIs, React
- Tools: Eclipse, IntelliJ IDEA, Visual Studio Code, R Studio
- Databases: Oracle PL/SQL, MySQL
- Others: GIT, SVN, JIRA, Trello

Work Experience:

GRADUATE TEACHING ASSITANT

DEPAUL UNIVERSITY, CHICAGO | JAN 2023 - PRESENT

- As a Graduate Teaching Assistant at DePaul University's Jarvis College of Computing and Digital Media, my primary responsibility is to assist undergraduate, graduate, and Ph.D. students in comprehending programming concepts.
- Utilized my extensive knowledge and experience in the field to facilitate learning and encouraged more than 100 students in the previous quarter to develop a deeper understanding of the subject matter.
- Also provided personalized guidance to help students achieve their academic goals and promote a collaborative learning environment.

NSI(NEW SYSTEM INFORMATION)

TCS, SWITZERLAND | JAN 2020 - DEC 2021

- Successfully addressed critical production incidents by determining the underlying cause and recommending necessary Java, SQL, and Data modifications, effectively mitigating system, and end-user impact by 40%.
- Worked on a data migration project utilizing **PL/SQL** and achieved a 60-70% improvement in overall migration time by identifying and optimizing inefficient processes through regular performance tuning and query optimization.
- Leveraged cutting-edge technologies including **Java**, **HTML**, **CSS**, and **Oracle** to optimize application functionality and enhance user experience which resulted in an impressive customer satisfaction index of over 95%.

NSI(NEW SYSTEM INFORMATION)

TCS, INDIA | JAN 2018 – DEC 2019

- Created technical specifications with possible solution approach for complex business requirements within the designated timeline, ensuring 100% on-time sprint delivery and improving project efficiency by 25%.
- Implemented multiple **PL/SQL** scripts to process business data requirements, integrated with scheduled Jenkins batch jobs for automatic execution.

GENERALI CLIENT PORTAL

TCS, INDIA | NOV 2016 - DEC 2017

- Developed and supported applications that were tailored to meet the specific needs and requirements of customers using Java,
 JavaScript, HTML, CSS, RESTful API, and Spring framework working alongside a cross-functional team size of around 25-30
 members.
- Written comprehensive **JUnit** test cases for conducting rigorous integration testing to ensure the bug-free performance of the applications with 100% test coverage.

PROJECTS | PROCESS IMPROVEMENTS

- Automated monitoring and management of **SVN** repository, integrated with **Jenkins** for batch job execution across multiple projects which reduced manual effort by **1-2 hours/day**, improved **CICD**, and increased overall efficiency.
- Constructed a **Google Chrome Extension** to streamline access to relevant links and applications for the project, improving overall efficiency by 5-10%.
- Designed and built a mobile app for the personal portfolio using the **Ionic** framework, through self-taught skills.